# Himanshu Shekhar

burnwalhimanshu@gmail.com / 8617829313 / Balewadi, Maharashtra

#### Summary

To associate with a progressive organization that gives me scope to update my knowledge in accordance with the latest trends and be part of a team that dynamically works towards the growth of the organization. I am keen to apply the knowledge, skills, and gain experience from the best possible position to contribute towards the success of the organization. My strengths are punctuality & responsibility, hardworking & adaptability. I always try to do something different. I never give up when faced with difficulty or setbacks.

## **Experience**

# Jr. Software Developer

Accelon Technologies Pvt Ltd. • Balewadi, Maharashtra

10/2023 - Present

- Assisting the development manager with all aspects of software design and coding.
- Attending and contributing to company development meetings.
- Writing and maintaining code.
- Working on minor bug fixes.
- Monitoring the technical performance of internal systems.
- Responding to requests from the development team.
- Gathering information from consumers about program functionality.
- · Writing reports.
- Conducting development tests.
- Working on XAML, C#, MS SQL Server, Fronnt end technologies, developing softwares similar to SAP B1.

## Software Developer Intern

JSpiders - Training & Development Center • Kolkata, West Bengal 10/2022 - 10/2023

Intensive Training on Softwares, Database Management and languages such as JAVA, SQL, HTML, CSS, JS etc.

# **Graphic Designer**

Vivela Stars • Asansol, West Bengal

08/2021 - 10/2021

• Maintained an updated design style allowing the company to scale to client and increase their revenue.

### **Education**

# Software & WEB Technology

QSpiders - Software Testing Training Institute • Salt Lake, West Bengal 10/2023

Got trained in SDLC, Oracle-SQL, Core Java, Manual Testing & Web Technology.

# Bachelor of technology

Maulana Abul Kalam Azad University of Technology • Shantiniketan, West Bengal 07/2023

- Received SVMCM merit Scholarship throughout the degree.
- · Achieved Distinction.

- Lead Final Year Project with the team of 20.
- Managed a Full-Time one year Internship with Academics.

## **Diploma in Enginneering**

The New Horizon Institute of Technology • Durgapur, West Bengal 07/2020

### **Matriculation**

Parasea Colliery High School, Parasea • Asansol, West Bengal 06/2017

#### **Skills**

Proficient in OSINT and WEBINT techniques., Excellent analytical and problem-solving skills., Effective communication and collaboration abilities, Strong understanding of Software Technologies.

### **Technical Skills**

- ASP.NET
- · Microsoft SQL Server
- · .NET MAUI
- · Code on Time
- · Software Systems
- Methodology
- · Web Applications
- SQL Database
- · Business Strategy
- Operations

# Languages

English, Hindi, Bengali

### Certificates

Deep-web, Java Full Stack Development

#### **Declaration**

I hereby declare that all the information provided in this CV is true and accurate to the best of my knowledge. I understand that any false statement may disqualify me from consideration for employment. I also authorize the verification of any information provided in this CV.

Date:		
Signature:		